Inventory of the Brown, Coalter, Tucker Papers (I) 1780-1929
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Group A: Coalter and Tucker Papers, 1780-1858., 6 boxes. (Box 1-6)
  - Children of John Coalter - Elizabeth Tucker Coalter and St. George Tucker Coalter; their spouses; children and other extended family, 1778-1852. (Box 4-5)
    - Box 5 - Continuing correspondence between the St. George Tucker Coalter and the John Randolph Bryan families: letters exchanged by the cousins, five Coalter children, and nine Bryan children. The controversy over the will of John Randolph of Roanoke is mentioned in several of the letters. St. 
      - F. T. Bryan, Eagle Point, to Frances Bland Coalter, 25 November 1851. (Box-folder 5:60)
        Fanny Coalter is attending a school conducted by Rev. Moses D. Hoge.
      - Virginia B. Coalter, Chericoke, to Betty, 7 December 1851. (Box-folder 5:61)
        Endorses note from Mrs. Judith H. Coalter.
      - Mrs. B. C. Lacy, Chatham and Eliwood, to Frances Bland Coalter, January-July 1852., 4 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 5:62)
        About her daughter, Agnes, and the progress on the improvements at Ellwood.
      - F. T. Bryan, Eagle Point, to Frances Bland Coalter, 7 January 1852. (Box-folder 5:63)
        "Rumors of a great revival at Mr. H.'s school have reached us from different quarters and report says Jinney and yourself acted a conspicuous part."
      - Mannie Tomlin, Lower Bremo, to Frances Bland Coalter, care of Rev. M. D. H., January-August 1852., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 5:64)
      - Sue Fickler, Fredericksburg, to Frances Balnd Coalter, February-December 1852., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 5:65)
        A school friend writes of her textbooks: "Paley's Moral Philosophy, Olinstead's Natural Philosophy, Hume's History of England, Conic Sections, Thompson's Arithmetic and French Studies."
      - Mrs. Judith H. Coalter to Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan, February-October 1852., 5 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 5:66)
        Includes a most interesting account of trip by boat from Gloucester County, via Jamestown, to Richmond.
      - Lucy Cocke, Lower Bremo, to Frances Bland Coalter, 1 March 1852., ALS. (Box-folder 5:67)
      - St. George Tucker Coalter, Rumford Academy, to Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan, March-October 1852., 4 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 5:68)
        The first letters written by Mrs. Coalter's youngest child.
      - John Coalter II, University of Virginia, to Frances Bland Coalter, 20 March 1852. (Box-folder 5:69)
      - Mannie Morton, Buffaloe, to Frances Bland Coalter, April-November l852., 6 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 5:70)
        A schoolmate who has left Rev. Mr. Hoge's school writes back.
      - St. George Tucker Coalter, Rumford Academy to Randolph Bryan, 4 May 1852. (Box-folder 5:71)
      - Rev. Moses D. Hoge, Richmond, to H[arrison] B. Tomlin, 8 October 1852. (Box-folder 5:72)
        An offer to abate charges so that Fanny B. Coalter could remain in school.
      - John Coalter II, Presley, to Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan, 2 November 1852. (Box-folder 5:73)
        Writes that he has stood his examination for license to practice law; reports on his brothers and sisters.
      - Mattie [Morton], Prince Edward, to Frances Bland Coalter, 20 December 1852. (Box-folder 5:74)
        Fanny has returned to Rev. Hoge's school; her friend writes regarding scarlet fever.
    Subseries 3: Grandchild of John Coalter
  - Grandchild of John Coalter - Frances Bland Coalter, daughter of St. George Tucker Coalter. Her correspondence gives a picture of mid-nineteenth century life and includes a near scandal in her attachment to her married schoolmaster, the Rev. Moses D. Hoge. The contents of this box end with the marriage of Frances Bland Coalter and Henry Peronneau Brown, Letters of Brown and his wife resume in Box 21, 1853-1858., 172 items. (Box 6:1-109)
    This box consists largely of papers collected by Frances Bland Coalter between February 1853, when she is preparing to leave school, and December 1858, when she married Henry Peronneau Brown. Through this marriage the Tucker-Coalter line was connected with the Brown line; thus, the papers of the two families were brought together into one.
    The collection gives an interesting picture of the life and interests of a young lady of moderate circumstances in the mid-l9th century. Of special interest are the letters concerning the Rev. Moses D. Hoge, whose school in Richmond Fanny Coalter had attended. Shortly after she left school, the Rev. Mr. Hoge carried on a very romantic correspondence with Fanny, although he was a married man with several children. The correspondence became more ardent in the early months of 1854 and, when Mrs. Hoge wrote that her husband had gone to Baltimore to stay with his brother who was ill, Fanny followed him there. According to the gossip of Mattie and Lizzie Morton, she went there to "entrap him." In October it was suggested that the brother, William Hoge, was the one in whom she was interested. The Rev. Mr. Hoge later sought to calm the fervours of his correspondent, as shown by his letters of 28 January 1855, 19 June 1856, and 19 March 1857.
    Fanny B. Coalter did not lack for other suitors, however, for she preserved a letter of 17 July 1854, a proposal of marriage from Alfred B. Tucker. A year later there are reports of her interest in the Brown brothers, John Thompson and Peronneau, of Petersburg, both of whom were courting her. She finally settled on the latter; some acceptances to the marriage invitation are included in this box.
    Letters of Frances Bland Coalter and her husband Henry Peronneau Brown continue in Box 21. The intervening boxes contain manuscripts of the Brown family, especially Capt. Henry Brown, grandfather of Henry Peronneau Brown (Boxes 7-13); the Hon. John Thompson Brown, father of Henry Peronneau Brown (Boxes 14-19); and Col. John Thompson Brown II, brother of Henry Peronneau Brown (Box 20).
    - Hess ( ), Ditchley, to Frances Bland Coalter, 8 February 1853. (Box-folder 6:1)
      Fanny is preparing to leave the school, having finished the course.
    - Josie McIlwaine and V[irginia] Braxton Coalter to Frances Bland Coalter, March-May 1853., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
      A schoolmate and Fanny's sister write after she leaves school.
    - Mrs. B.C. Lacy, Eliwood and Chatham, to Frances Bland Coalter, April-November 1853., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:3)
    - Betty Braxton, Chericoke, to Virginia B. Coalter, 31 May 1853. (Box-folder 6:4)
      Reports that Jack Bryan, oldest son of Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan is dying at the Coalter home, Presley.
    - Mrs. Judith H. Coalter, Stanley, to Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan, June-December 1853., 4 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:5)
      After many years of waiting (since the death of her husband in 1839) Mrs. Coalter is finally able to buy her own place, Stanley. She tells of her move and of the illness that put her in bed afterward.
    - Sallie [Gaines], Powhite, to Frances Bland Coalter, 18 June 1853. (Box-folder 6:6)
    - J. T. Morton and Lizzie, Buffaloe, to Frances Bland Coalter, 15 July 1853. (Box-folder 6:7)
    - Fanny W. Gaines, Powhite, to Fannie [Coalter], 16 July 1853. (Box-folder 6:8)
    - [Rev.] Moses D. Hoge, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 20 July 1853. (Box-folder 6:9)
      The school is closed for the summer, his wife and children are away, so he enlivens his solitude "by having a little chat with you...and where I always think of you and the delightful morning when we enjoyed the scene together...how I cherish every memorial of you. "I greatly enjoyed your last brief visit to us and that evening (do you remember it?) when the music room being full of company we found quiet, and cool breezes in the back porch. I have been sitting there tonight." (A strange letter, indeed, and one which was to cause some upset in the heart of Frances Bland Coalter, as subsequent correspondence show.)
    - Frances Bland Coalter, Stanley, to "My own dear Aunt" [Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan], 18 November 1853. (Box-folder 6:10)
    - James K. Lee, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 29 November 1853. (Box-folder 6:11)
    - Hess ( ) to "My dear sister" [Mrs. Judith H. Coalter], [November] 1853. (Box-folder 6:12)
      Written to Mrs. Judith H. Coalter soon after she purchased her home, Stanley.
    - Rev. M.D. Hoge, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 20 December 1853. (Box-folder 6:13)
      "This letter cannot hold any news, so I will fill it with love...entertaining myself by wishing that you could walk into the room and occupy a vacant chair hard by ."I hope to see you sometimes...nothing to what I would enjoy were I to keep house in a quiet way and have you for my guest a week at a time..."I would like you to marry some fine fellow and live in Richmond, only I...like you best as you are, except that you are too far from me."
    - Rev. M. D. Hoge, Hampstead, to Frances Bland Coalter, [January] 1854. (Box-folder 6:14)
      "When I woke up yesterday morning and found it raining, my spirits fell as low as the mercury for I feared you would not come to Hampstead..."
    - Lizzie Morton, Buffaloe and Petersburg, to Frances Bland Coalter, February 1854., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:15)
    - Rev. M. D. Hoge, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 23 March 1854. (Box-folder 6:16)
      "You ask me why it is that I am so partial to you--well, the very first time we get a chance to have a talk by ourselves I will tell you...When shall the opportunity come? There is always so much company at your house..."
    - John Coalter II, Stanley Hall, to Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan, April, July 1854., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:17)
      He conducts a school: "I succeeded in six days of raising 21 scholars." He writes that Henry has graduated in Law with distinction.
    - Mrs. Susan M. Hoge to Fanny [Bland Coalter], [April] 1854. (Box-folder 6:18)
      "I think from his letter, Brother [William Hoge] has been much sicker than we had any idea of Mr. [Moses D.] Hoge is going on Thursday to see him and will probably remain in Baltimore until he is well enough to travel..."
    - Mattie [Morton], Buffaloe, to Frances Bland Coalter, 27 April 1854. (Box-folder 6:19)
      Addressed to Fanny at Baltimore. Her friend writes, "Cousin Joe says you went to Baltimore purposely to see Mr. Hoge."
    - Sallie [W. Gaines], Powhite, to Frances Bland Coalter, 12 June 1854., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:20)
      Reports gossip concerning Fanny's Baltimore trip.
    - F[annie] W. Gaines, Powhite, to Fannie [Bland Coalter], 24 June 1854. (Box-folder 6:21)
    - Rev. M. D. Hoge, New York, to Frances Bland Coalter, 24 June 1854. (Box-folder 6:22)
      "Often when (I am) abroad, you will be in my mind and heart. Neither do I want you to get married before I return. I am to perform that service, you know..."
    - Lizzie Morton, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 29 June 1854. (Box-folder 6:23)
      Concerning the gossip regarding Fanny and Rev. Hoge: "Surely you could not think me so deceitful as to profess to love you and then say that you would try to entrap a gentleman. I did not say so. I remember saying that if you went to Baltimore and were thrown with Mr. Hoge I believed he would address you, because I know he admired you very sincerely..."
    - Alfred B. Tucker, Winchester, to Fanny [B. Coalter], 17 July 1854. (Box-folder 6:24)
      A proposal of marriage.
    - Mrs. Betty C. Lacy, Ellwood, to Frances Bland Coalter, 19 July 1854. (Box-folder 6:25)
    - J. Horace Lacy, Ellwood, to Frances Bland Coalter, 22 August 1854. (Box-folder 6:26)
      A rumor that Frances Bland Coalter is to marry.
    - F[rances] T[ucker] Bryan, Rockbridge, to Frances Bland Coalter, 8 September 1854. (Box-folder 6:27)
    - Mattie H. Morton, Buffaloe, to Frances Bland Coalter, 3 October 1854. (Box-folder 6:28)
      "Julia Green was here...when I told her that you had gotten a letter from Mr. Hoge she said she was so jealous of you that she was ready to fight..."
    - Sallie W. Gaines, Powhite, to F. B. Coalter, 6 October 1854. (Box-folder 6:29)
      "I am going to Baltimore...and I shall see Mr. Wm. Hoge! Don't you wish you were going? What shall I tell him for you?"
    - St. G[eorge] T. Coalter, Boswell, to Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan, 23 October 1854. (Box-folder 6:30)
      St. George is now in school at Staunton.
    - A. Steven, Jr., Charlottesville, to Col. [Harrison] Tomlin, 12 January 1855. (Box-folder 6:31)
      Construction work to be done at the University of Virginia.
    - Rev. M. D. Hoge to Frances Bland Coalter, 28 January 1855. (Box-folder 6:32)
      "I hope that it will not be long before I have the pleasure of seeing you, my dear and constantly remembered friend."
    - Mattie Morton, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, February-September 1855., 4 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:33)
    - Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan, Eagle Point, to Frances Bland Coalter, 12 February 1855. (Box-folder 6:34)
    - Mrs. B.C. Lacy, Ellwood, to Frances Bland Coalter, February-December 1855., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:35)
      "I have heard several times of your engagement to Thomas--who has made himself very scarce."
    - Betty Braxton, Oak Springs, to Frances Bland Coalter, April-( ) 1855., 9 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:36)
    - Sue [Taliaferro], Belle Ville, to [Frances Bland Coalter], 28 May 1855. (Box-folder 6:37)
      Accepts invitation to the marriage of Virginia, younger sister of Fanny Coalter.
    - Sallie [Gaines], Powhite, to Frances Bland Coalter, 25 June 1855. (Box-folder 6:38)
    - W. Hall to Frances Bland Coalter, 28 June 1855. (Box-folder 6:39)
    - Mrs. B.C. Lacy, Eliwood, to Frances Bland Coalter, 29 July 1855. (Box-folder 6:40)
    - Frances Bland Coalter, Salt Sulphur Springs, to Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan, 1 September 1855. (Box-folder 6:41)
    - Betty Braxton, Chericoke, to Franes Bland Coalter, November, December 1855., 2 letters. ALS. Covers lacking. (Box-folder 6:42)
    - Henry T. Coalter, Gloucester Court House, to Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan, 21 November 1855. (Box-folder 6:43)
      Now a practicing lawyer, he writes to his aunt on business.
    - Lucy T. Braxton, Philadelphia, to Frances Bland Coalter, 10 December 1855. (Box-folder 6:44)
    - Fanny C. Braxton, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, December 1855., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:45)
      To her cousin regarding "Mr. President" and "The Vice." (This appears to refer to the Brown brothers, John Thompson and Henry Peronneau. Frances Bland Coalter was to marry the latter.)
    - J[ohn] T[hompson] Brown to Frances Bland Coalter, (?) 1855. (Box-folder 6:46)
      "I wish you to be very particular in your conversations with P[eronneau] not to let him have the least idea of the tenor of my remarks to you yesterday and at the same time manage to convince him that I am not in love with you, as I am afraid such is his present opinion."
    - Sue Carter, Pampatike, to Frances Bland Coalter (?) 1855., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:47)
    - H. B. Tomlin, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 9 January 1856. (Box-folder 6:48)
    - Mrs. Elizabeth Bryan, Eagle Point, to Mrs. St. George Coalter, 15 February 1856. (Box-folder 6:49)
      Trouble in: finding a teacher for her children; "the Roanoke business"--(evidently a reference to the still unsettled will of John Randolph of Roanoke.)
    - Mrs. B. C. Lacy, Chatham, to Frances Bland Coalter, February, December 1856., 2 letters. ALS. Covers lacking. (Box-folder 6:50)
      Concerned about the health of Fanny's mother, has a horror of those "distracting springs" for invalids.
    - Thomas H. Carter and James P. Roy, Chericoke, to Frances Bland Coalter, 14 March 1856. (Box-folder 6:51)
      The solution to a problem in surveying (this may be the "Thomas" to whom Frances Bland Coalter was rumored to be engaged).
    - Alex Martin, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 22 April 1856. (Box-folder 6:52)
      On the death of Mrs. E. T. Bryan, aunt of Fanny Bland Coalter.
    - "Cousin Sue," Oak Spring, to Frances Bland Coalter, 2 May 1856. (Box-folder 6:53)
    - Ann E. T. Magill, Winchester, to Frances Bland Coalter, 7 May 1856. (Box-folder 6:54)
      On the death of Mrs. Elizabeth T. Bryan.
    - J. H. L[acy], Ellwood, to Frances Bland Coalter, 13 May 1856. (Box-folder 6:55)
    - Georgia Bryan, Eagle Point, to Frances Bland Coalter, June-July 1856., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:56)
      Thanks Fanny for her help at the time of the death of Mrs. Bryan, her mother.
    - F. T. Bryan, Eagle Point, to Mrs. St. George Tucker Coalter, 10 June 1856. (Box-folder 6:57)
      Is in charge of the plantation since her mother's death; busy making summer clothes for the slaves.
    - Rev. M. D. Hoge, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 19 June 1856. (Box-folder 6:58)
      Suggests a visit together to "cousin Horace Lacy."
    - Sue S. Taliaferro, Belle Ville, to Frances Bland Coalter, 20 June 1856. (Box-folder 6:59)
    - Betty Braxton, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 26 June 1856. (Box-folder 6:60)
      P[eronneau] Brown and his brother, Thompson, are mentioned. (See letters of December 1855, Box-folder 6:44-45.)
    - Joseph R. Bryan, Eagle Point, to Mrs. St. George Tucker Coalter (J. H. C.), 2 July 1856. (Box-folder 6:61)
      Writes to ask Mrs. Coalter to stay with his daughters during his absence in the south.
    - J. F. Morton, Farmville, to Frances Bland Coalter, 23 July 1856. (Box-folder 6:62)
    - Fanny C. Braxton, Bremo, to Frances Bland Coalter, 2 August 1856. (Box-folder 6:63)
    - Georgia L. Bryan, Savannah, Ga., to Mrs. St. George Tucker Coalter, 31 January 1857. (Box-folder 6:64)
    - Mrs. Delia B[ryan] Page, Eagle Point, to Frances Bland Coalter, 28 February 1857. (Box-folder 6:65)
      Has charge of the large plantation, keeping four seamstresses, three spinners and a weaver busy.
    - Mrs. Betty B[ryan] Daliam, Baltimore, to Frances Bland Coalter, 9 March 1857. (Box-folder 6:66)
    - Mrs. B. C. Lacy, Eliwood, to Frances Bland Coalter, March, December 1857., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:67)
    - Rev. M.D. Hoge to Frances Bland Coalter, 19 March 1857. (Box-folder 6:68)
      "No, my dear Fanny, my affection for you has not changed."
    - Josie McIl[waine], Petersburg, to Frances Bland Coalter, March, October 1857., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:69)
      Regarding Mr. Willcox Brown and his brother Peronneau, future husband of Frances Bland Coalter.
    - J. F. Mcllwaine to [Frances Bland Coalter], 11 June 1857. (Box-folder 6:70)
      Invitation to the commencement party at Hampden Sidney College.
    - G[eorgia] L. Bryan, Eagle Point, to Frances Bland Coalter, July-October 1857., 3 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:71)
    - Lucy T. Braxton, Staunton, to Frances Bland Coalter, July, August 1857., 2 letters. ALS. Covers lacking. (Box-folder 6:72)
    - J. H. Lacy, Fredericksburg, to Frances Bland Coalter, 7 August 1857. (Box-folder 6:73)
    - H[arrison] B. Tomlin, Staunton, to Frances Bland Coalter, 23 September 1857. (Box-folder 6:74)
    - Mary T. Magill, Winchester, to Frances Bland Coalter, 26 September 1857. (Box-folder 6:75)
    - J. H. Lacy, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 15 October 1857. (Box-folder 6:76)
    - Mattie H. Morton, Buffaloe, to Frances Bland Coalter, October, November 1857., 2 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:77)
    - "Jennie," Belmead, to Frances Bland Coalter, 6 December 1857. (Box-folder 6:78)
    - E. Martin to Frances Bland Coalter, 18 December 1857. (Box-folder 6:79)
    - N. Morson, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, [December] 1857. (Box-folder 6:80)
    - H. B. Tomlin and John Coalter II, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 16 January 1858. (Box-folder 6:81)
    - John Coalter II, Bascobel, Louisiana, to Frances Bland Coalter, 10 February 1858. (Box-folder 6:82)
      Accompanying his uncle on a business trip, he has visited the main cities of the south and attended the opera in New Orleans. "I must confess that I have been rather disappointed in the people that live in these rich lands--they are as rough as possible...live in log houses and on the very poorest fare."
    - H. B. Tomlin, [Richmond], to Frances Bland Coalter, February 1858. (Box-folder 6:83)
    - J. Mcllwaine to Frances Bland Coalter, 11 March 1858. (Box-folder 6:84)
    - G[eorgia] L. Bryan, Warner Hall, to Frances Bland Coalter, 10 April 1858. (Box-folder 6:85)
    - F. C. Means, Fairfield, to Frances Bland Coalter, 6 May 1858. (Box-folder 6:86)
    - Mary T. Magill, Winchester, to Frances Bland Coalter, May-November 1858., 4 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:87)
      "I suppose your wedding will be postponed unless Mr. Brown's recovery is unusually rapid."
    - Lucie [Gaines], Powhite, to Frances Bland Coalter, 18 June 1858. (Box-folder 6:88)
    - Cousin "F. B. M." to Frances Bland Coalter, 23 July 1858. (Box-folder 6:89)
    - Helen Fitzhugh, Alum Springs, to Fanny Bland Coalter, 5 August 1858. (Box-folder 6:90)
    - Mrs. J. H. Coalter, Staunton, to Frances Bland Coalter, 20 August 1858. (Box-folder 6:91)
    - Lucy T. Braxton, White Sulphur Springs, to Frances Bland Coalter, [August] 1858., 4 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:92)
    - Mrs. Betty B. Dallam, Baltimore, to Frances Bland Coalter, 1 September 1858. (Box-folder 6:93)
      "The news of your engagement [to Henry P. Brown] did not surprise me...how heartily I approve of your choice..."
    - F. T. Bryan, Cargobrook, to Frances Bland Coalter, 21 September 1858. (Box-folder 6:94)
    - Mrs. B.C. Lacy, Ellwood, to Frances Bland Coalter, September-December 1858., 3 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:95)
      "If my letter arrives too late for Miss Fanny Coalter, I hope Mrs. Brown will have enough affection for the old name to lay claim to it."
    - Eliza P. Willcox, Fleur de Hundred, to Frances Bland Coalter, 29 October 1858. (Box-folder 6:96)
    - Ann Eliza [Fitzhugh Gordon], Fredericksburg, to Frances Bland Coalter, 29 October 1858. (Box-folder 6:97)
    - Mattie [Morton], Buffaloe, to Frances Bland Coalter, 8 November 1858 (Box-folder 6:98)
    - Alfred B. Tucker, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 3 December 1858. (Box-folder 6:99)
      Regrets that he cannot attend the wedding.
    - Mrs. Virginia S. Brooke, Ashland, to Frances Bland Coalter, 4 December 1858. (Box-folder 6:100)
    - S. G. Carrington, Richmond, to Frances Bland Coalter, 6 December 1858. (Box-folder 6:101)
    - Elthu M. Higgins, Farmville, to Frances Bland Coalter, n.d. (Box-folder 6:102)
      This letter is undated but probably received before December 7, 1858.
    - F. T. Bryan, W[arner] Hall, to Frances Bland Coalter, n.d. (Box-folder 6:103)
    - M. [H. Morton], Buffaloe, to Frances Bland Coalter, n.d. (Box-folder 6:104)
    - S. [Gaines], Powhite, to Frances Bland Coalter, n.d., 7 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:105)
      These letters are undated but probably received before December 7, 1858.
    - Betty Vice to Frances Bland Coalter, n.d. (Box-folder 6:106)
    - Jack, "Perfect Misery" and "M" [to Frances Bland Coalter], n.d., 3 letters. ALS. (Box-folder 6:107)
    - "The King Wm. and Hanover Charaders. Positively their last appearance. At Stanley on Friday evening the 9th this brilliant Company....Ticket 1 ct., children and servants half price." A home performance by the Coalter and Bryan cousins, n.d. (Box-folder 6:108)
      This item is undated but probably received before December 7, 1858.
    - Covers addressed to Miss Fanny B. Coalter, n.d., 17 items. ALS. (Box-folder 6:109)
      These covers are undated but probably received before December 7, 1858.
  Series 2: Group B
- Group B: Capt. Henry Brown and Brown Family Papers, 1774-1848., 7 boxes. (Box 7-13)